<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tom Whipple]]></title>
  <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-20T16:05:05-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tomwhipple.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tom Whipple]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[IPython Notebook: the awesomest mathematical programming tool EVER]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2013/01/ipython-notebook-the-awesomest-mathematical-programming-tool-ever/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-27T19:37:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2013/01/ipython-notebook-the-awesomest-mathematical-programming-tool-ever</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yes, that&#8217;s a bold claim. But I stand by it. I&#8217;ll skip straight to the important part:</p>

<p><a href="http://ipython.org">IPython Notebook</a> makes it dead simple to explore your code/data. Just look at my <a href="http://tomwhipple.com/projects/explorations/basic-signal-processing-with-ipython-notebook.html">simple signal processing example</a>.</p>

<p>Intrigued? If you&#8217;ve already installed IPython (and numpy/scipy and matplotlib), you&#8217;ve already got it! Just start notebook:</p>

<p><code>$ ipython notebook --pylab inline</code></p>

<p>The notebook console will open in a browser window. (Ok, you might need a couple more dependencies, but how hard is that??)</p>

<p>Then all you have to do is <a href="http://tomwhipple.com/projects/explorations/basic-signal-processing-example.ipynb">download the notebook</a> and <strong>drag it to the console browser window!</strong> How awesome is that?!</p>

<p>And, if that isn&#8217;t enough, a lot of work has been put into it&#8217;s multi-processing abilities. It is well worth the time to <a href="http://ipython.org/videos.html">watch the introductory video</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guest post at Testdroid: Using Testdroid Cloud to test a camera SDK]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2012/11/guest-post-at-testdroid-using-testdroid-cloud-to-test-a-camera-sdk/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-26T07:38:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2012/11/guest-post-at-testdroid-using-testdroid-cloud-to-test-a-camera-sdk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The great people at <a href="http://testdroid.com">Testdroid</a> asked me to write a <a href="http://testdroid.com/testdroid/3524/guest-blog-post-using-testdroid-cloud-to-test-a-camera-sdk">guest post</a> about our experience with their product.</p>

<blockquote><p>Developing an SDK that makes heavy use of the camera is different from typical Android app development. First, developing an SDK means that we have to think about ease of integration with other apps. For example, things like XML layouts and <code>R.drawable</code> are not available to us, since we don&#8217;t want any unnecessary integration steps. Second, we are doing on-device computer vision, so we have a lot of highly optimized C and even some hand written assembly which must be compiled with the NDK and linked via JNI. And, if you&#8217;ve been fortunate to work with the Android native layer, you know that the toolchain is not quite as stable as the Java SDK. Finally, we&#8217;re doing frame by frame processing with the camera. Obviously, the camera is a piece of hardware that has been implemented differently by each manufacturer, so there are inevitably some differences in behavior if it is accessed in a way that is not quite as intended.</p>

<p><a href="http://testdroid.com/testdroid/3524/guest-blog-post-using-testdroid-cloud-to-test-a-camera-sdk">more</a></p></blockquote>

<p>For small app developers, it is well worth the $100 or so to test on a bunch of different devices, even if you only run the tests once per major release. You&#8217;ll wish you had done it sooner.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Site updated...  Finally!]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2012/11/updated-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2012/11/updated-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey, I&#8217;m still alive!</p>

<p>Seriously though, the site has been updated to use <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>, and is how hosted on <a href="http://pages.github.com">GitHub pages</a>.</p>

<p>Content is typically written in raw text (markdown). The framework generates static HTML from these files, which can be served on any web server. The result is that all the site admin headaches for systems like <a href="http://wordpress.org">Wordpress</a> are eliminated. And, if the site is served via GitHub, authentication is handled via SSH keys.</p>

<p>Can it get any easier than that?</p>

<p>BTW: If you&#8217;re really curious, the source for this site is <a href="https://github.com/tomwhipple/octopress/tree/tomwhipple">on GitHub</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Etiquette for Recruiters]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2011/05/etiquette-for-recruiters/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2011/05/etiquette-for-recruiters</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Ok, here are some dos &amp; don&#8217;ts for all you recruiters out there:
<ul>
	<li><strong>DON&#8217;T cold call me just because I&#8217;ve just connected with someone you know on LinkedIn.</strong></li>
	<li>DON&#8217;T pretend that I should know who you are. - If you&#8217;ve never spoken to me before, an introduction is appropriate.</li>
	<li>DON&#8217;T just use random keywords from my blog and profile and assume they define me. Just because I&#8217;ve written about an SEO talk I went to two years ago doesn&#8217;t mean that I do SEO a living. (Hint: My resume &amp; profile talk about software development. SEO is <em>not</em> software development).</li>
	<li>DON&#8217;T just pass on my name and number to a co-worker without any context.</li>
	<li>DO <em>email</em> me with an introduction and specific details and, if you must call, ask for a good  time to do so.</li>
	<li>DO know who I am and what I do <em>before</em> you call.</li>
	<li>DO understand that my time is valuable and that, as a contractor,  I&#8217;m losing money if I&#8217;m talking to you.</li>
</ul>
(And in case you are thinking about contacting me, I&#8217;m not looking for new opportunities at the moment.)
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Search Engine Optimization]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2009/08/on-search-engine-optimization/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2009/08/on-search-engine-optimization</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Search engine optimization (SEO) is important. (Duh!) But, being a developer I never spent much time thinking about these things. However, with my new ventures I am now in a position to actually care about search results.

To that end, on Wednesday I attended a talk/networking event at Yahoo&#8217;s Santa Monica office given by <a href="http://www.ninebyblue.com/">Vanessa Fox</a> of  <a href="http://janeandrobot.com">janeandrobot.com</a>. The discussion was informal, yet informative even for one who has just begun to be interested in SEO. I learned several things, many of which are available elsewhere on the web, but I will repeat them here in no particular order:
<ul>
	<li>The guiding principle of SEO is similar to that of journalism: For each page, imagine that the user has just landed there and not seen any other pages of the site.</li>
	<li>The consensus amongst the group was that the only search engine that matters is Google. Yahoo is nearly irrelevant. Bing/Microsoft does not yet have their act together.</li>
	<li>The most important features of a page are url, &lt;title&gt;, &lt;h1&gt;, and meta description. URLs should be vaguely descriptive (i.e. not something like store?prodid=12)</li>
	<li>Text should be unique (especially the text in the above features).</li>
	<li>Ads are bad.</li>
</ul>
And, a few resources that I have found in the past few days:
<ol>
	<li><a href="http://www.google.com/webmasters/docs/search-engine-optimization-starter-guide.pdf">Google&#8217;s best practice document [pdf]</a></li>
	<li><a href="http://janeandrobot.com/resources">janeandrobot.com/resources</a> (note how the URL exactly describes what it is!)</li>
	<li><a href="http://siteexplorer.search.yahoo.com/">Yahoo&#8217;s site explorer</a></li>
	<li>Google site search - ie google &#8220;site:yourdomain.com&#8221;. Are you happy with the way things look in the result? If not, edit the meta description.</li>
	<li>Of course, Google&#8217;s free webmaster and analytics tools. (signup required)</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing Smartovation Technologies!]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2009/08/announcing-smartovation-technologies/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2009/08/announcing-smartovation-technologies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am very pleased to announce the launch of <a title="Smartovation Technologies" href="http://www.smartovation.com">Smartovation Technologies</a>, a new venture devoted to iPhone and web applications. We expect to be able to submit at least one new App this month. Stay tuned for updates!</p>

<p>And, work continues on the <a href="http://www.walki-talki.com">walki-talk.com</a> audio tour guides.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flaws of Linux ...]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2009/08/flaws-of-linux/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2009/08/flaws-of-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[This, in a nutshell, is why Linux will <em>never</em> take over.

<a href="http://xkcd.com/619/"><img src="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/supported_features.png" height="326" width="324" /></a>

[<a href="http://xkcd.com/619/">xkcd.com</a>] 
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Walki-Talki.com London tour available on the App Store]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2009/07/walki-talkicom-london-tour-available-on-the-app-store/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2009/07/walki-talkicom-london-tour-available-on-the-app-store</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center"><img src="http://walki-talki.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/london_iphone.png" title="London App screen shot" alt="London App screen shot" height="384" width="200" /></p>
Last night I learned that <a href="http://www.walki-talki.com">walki-talki.com</a>&#8217;s walking tour of London was just approved by Apple for release and <a href="itms://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=320626439&amp;mt=8&amp;s=143441">posted to the App Store</a>. I won&#8217;t re-post all of the details (<a href="http://walki-talki.com/wordpress/2009/07/04/walki-talki-releases-london-tour-for-the-iphone/">you can check them out here</a>). But I will say that it&#8217;s about time!! Apple has taken nearly 2 weeks to approve this app, but has not yet approved our Amsterdam tour, despite it being submitted a month earlier! Anyway, enough griping. We are very pleased to be making progress.
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WWDC Party & Day 5]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2009/06/wwdc-party-day-5/"/>
    <updated>2009-06-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2009/06/wwdc-party-day-5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[The party last night was great! Cake (the band, not the food) played for us for a little more than an hour. I took some pictures, but iPhoto is crashing when I try to download them. (Hey Apple, what&#8217;s up with that?) It was a true geek party in that the ratio of men to women was about 100:1. One woman actually took a picture of the huge line for the men&#8217;s room. (Needless to say, there were no lines for the women&#8217;s.)

This morning I focused on fixing bugs in our app, both serious and trivial. I got some great advice on how to properly design the internals of the application to take full advantage of Apple&#8217;s architecture. The Apple engineers have been an enormously valuable source of information from quick tips &amp; tricks to detailed answers.

Today&#8217;s lunchtime speaker was Neil Young (no, not the singer), CEO of <a href="http://blog.ngmoco.com/">Ngmoco</a>. This company was founded in March 2008, as a direct result of the release of the iPhoneOS 2.0, SDK &amp; App Store. It was interesting to hear how quickly they were able to put the whole thing together and begin earning revenue.
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WWDC Day 4: Lots of good stuff]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2009/06/wwdc-day-4-lots-of-good-stuff/"/>
    <updated>2009-06-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2009/06/wwdc-day-4-lots-of-good-stuff</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Wow. We covered a lot of good material today. From advanced debugging techniques to recommendations for best practices in app design it was all very helpful, though again quite boring to a non-developer audience.

The lunchtime talk was about a <a href="http://www.moonviews.com/">techno-archeology project</a> is using Macs to reconstruct moon image data from original NASA analog recordings. The central problem they experienced is that although the media is in good shape, there were no tape machines capable of reading it! Fortunately a couple of units were found in storage on military facilities and were able to be rebuilt for the task.

I&#8217;ll keep this one short as the next presentation is starting now. After this it&#8217;s party time!!
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WWDC: How not to do marketing ...]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2009/06/wwdc-how-not-to-do-marketing/"/>
    <updated>2009-06-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2009/06/wwdc-how-not-to-do-marketing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Ok, if you are going to hand out cards inviting all the conference attendees to a &#8220;party&#8221; (i.e. captive demo) and promise free drinks &amp; appetizers, it is a good idea to make sure you have enough free drinks and appetizers to go around. After all, if you can&#8217;t organize a party, how can I possibly believe that you can build a functional product.

I&#8217;m talking to you Parallez &amp; Appcellerator (or however you spell it).

We&#8217;ll see if tonight is any better &#8230;
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WWDC Day 3: Geek details & iPhone orchestra]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2009/06/wwdc-day-3-geek-details-iphone-orchestra/"/>
    <updated>2009-06-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2009/06/wwdc-day-3-geek-details-iphone-orchestra</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Today brought a lot of technical details which were important but very boring to the casual audience. I spent a good chunk of time in the iPhone lab, talking to Apple engineers and others while fixing bugs in our app. Plus, one of the sessions gave me a bunch of ideas to improve the performance and look of the app. Hopefully we can start getting them approved very soon!

The highlight of the day from a theatrical perspective was the lunchtime talk given by Dr. Ge Wang, CTO of <a href="http://www.smule.com/">Smule</a>. The apps produced by Smule are audio related, from the sonic lighter (a flame that you can blow out by blowing on the iPhone microphone) to various instruments that are played by pressing various &#8220;holes&#8221; or sliders on the iPhone screen and blowing into the microphone. There are a lot of other neat features, like being able to hear &amp; see music played by others across the world, but I won&#8217;t go into all the details.

The interesting part of this story is that in less than a year, one of their apps was downloaded over one million times. At $0.99 each, less 30% to Apple, that works out to be $700,000 from a single app. Not too bad for a company that didn&#8217;t exist a year ago. So, it seems clear that if you can produce a compelling app, there is money to be made. The question is then what makes a compelling app. Clearly a flame that &#8220;burns&#8221; on the screen has no useful value, yet many people paid for it. Of course most in the audience were no doubt thinking along the same line.

Nonetheless, we were treated to a performance by the Stanford Mobile Phone Orchestra (or MoPho). It was &#8230; interesting. I took some photos, but they are unbelievably bad. Perhaps if I had an iPhone 3GS they would have turned out.
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WWDC Day 2: Games, Networking and more]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2009/06/day-2-games-networking-and-more/"/>
    <updated>2009-06-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2009/06/day-2-games-networking-and-more</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Today, I attended a session on networking and a couple of game overview sessions. The networking session was interesting, though not in a way that any non-developers would care about. The games sessions were interesting, since I haven&#8217;t done much in the way of game development in the past, though this may change.

The capabilities of the new OS, especially with the new hardware are absolutely fantastic. We&#8217;ve had accelerometer control since forever, which is just neat. Now, we add peer to peer gaming via bluetooth or WiFi so that users can have multi-player games across the room or across the world. The new phone adds a GPU, allowing amazing video effects. The addition of OpenAL means that 3D sound can be part of the game experience as well. (There&#8217;s also a magnetometer/compass, though it isn&#8217;t clear how that helps game development, but I&#8217;m sure someone will do something cool with it.) In one of the sessions yesterday it was mentioned that a high percentage of the apps up on the App Store are games. It is clear that Apple recognizes that the iPhone is not just a smart phone, but is poised to become a leading mobile game platform as well.

In many of the sessions, I find myself pulling out my iPhone or MacBook to jot down another idea for an application or product. Apple has provided developers with a lot of tools to express their creativity without having to keep track of minor details. It makes the idea of going back to the day job even more depressing, since I know that my employer has no incentive or motivation to explore these technologies, even though they could be tremendously useful. (No doubt there will be a post on this topic at some point in the future, though probably not soon.)

On an unrelated note, I was able to fix a serious bug in an app I have in development after talking to some of the Apple engineers in a lab. And, we don&#8217;t even have to mandate 3.0 for our users as I first feared. Now, I just have to re-submit the fixed version and then off to find a party&#8230;
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WWDC Day 1: Long lines & Keynote]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2009/06/wwdc-day-1-long-lines-keynote/"/>
    <updated>2009-06-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2009/06/wwdc-day-1-long-lines-keynote</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Well, I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve seen so many geeks in one place. Not even engineering school! As I write this I am sitting on the second floor of the Moscone convention center watching a couple hundred guys (oh and I can see 4 women &#8211; wait there&#8217;s another!) with their Macs out, posting on their blogs. (Yep, that includes me.)

The morning got off to a disappointing start when arrived to find the line wrapped all the way around the block. Unfortunately, it didn&#8217;t start moving until about 5 minutes before the keynote started, which meant that those of us that didn&#8217;t arrive at some obscene hour of the morning didn&#8217;t get seated in an overflow room until about 15 minutes in. We missed the launch of a couple of new Macs, but web feeds indicated it wasn&#8217;t anything too revolutionary - just the latest laptop lineup. I talked to a guy who started lining up at 3am(!!), so maybe the overflow room isn&#8217;t so bad.

We first learned about the new version of OSX (code name: Snow Leopard). It looks like there are going to be a lot of nifty enhancements to the UI in the Finder, Preview, Safari, and Quicktime. The case for the new Safari was particularly compelling if the claims about page rendering performance hold up. Since it will ship today, I&#8217;ll probably switch back from Firefox and see how it goes.

However the OS enhancements that look like they may be the most exciting for developers are the features related to multi-threading, multi-core, 64 bit support, and most interesting, the announcement of what Apple is calling OpenCL. This is a new <em>open</em> standard that Apple is releasing to the community, which is designed to allow non-graphics applications to use the GPU for their computations. This will be huge for scientific computing (hopefully Matlab) as well as programs like Photoshop. It will be interesting to see how Apple applies this technology to the MacBook Air, which has no GPU. Unfortunately, very few details were given for these features. Maybe we will learn more in this afternoon&#8217;s sessions.

The last part of the Keynote was about the reason I&#8217;m here: The iPhone. There are many new neat features that will open up a huge number of possibilities for all of us here. Some of the highlights are: peer to peer via bluetooth, opening up support for accessory hardware, and support sharing the cell network to your laptop and MMS support, pending carrier support. But, unlike the rest of the carriers in the world, it turns out that AT&amp;T won&#8217;t be supporting these technologies right away. This revelation drew laughs and heckles from the crowd. I sincerely hope that someone from AT&amp;T was in the room to hear it, since I&#8217;m pretty sure that most of us would drop our AT&amp;T contract in a second if there was another US carrier that supported the iPhone.

Finally, a new model of the iPhone was introduced. The new phone will have a faster processor, better camera and voice recognition. Of course everyone (including me) will want the new one, so I&#8217;m wondering who I can sell my current 16GB iPhone 3G to. It was also announced that the price of the current 4GB iPhone 3G would drop to $99.

<em> AFTERNOON UPDATE:  </em>The only way to describe the new developer tools: kick ass. The static analysis tools are revolutionary; the software can automatically find bugs like memory leaks and even logic errors without even running the code. This is amazing, both in terms of technology and ease of use. I can&#8217;t wait to try it.
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone code signing problems]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2008/11/iphone-code-signing-problems/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-11T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2008/11/iphone-code-signing-problems</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<em>UPDATE: If you think it should work and it continues to cause problems, use the windows solution (i.e. reboot everything) and do a clean build. Here is a more current <a href="http://www.24100.net/2009/02/iphone-sdk-mobile-provisioning-0xe800003a-0xe8000001/">discussion</a>.</em>

As many developers have figured out by now, iPhone code signing is unnecessarily difficult. To make matters worse, it doesn&#8217;t sound like Apple is very responsive to their developers. (In my case they have yet to get back to me after two days.) A couple of key points:
<ol>
	<li>In the main XCode screen, highlight Targets-&gt;AppName, and click the info button. Under Build, the &#8220;Code Signing Identity&#8221; must <em>exactly</em> match the certificate name from the certificate manager.An Open Question: Does this value get inherited from the project values?</li>
	<li>The Resources-&gt;info.plist file must have the correct app id. In my case
com.tomwhipple.${PRODUCT_NAME:identifier}</li>
</ol>
A couple of more detailed discussions:
<ul>
	<li><a href="http://www.talentgrouplabs.com/blog/archive/2008/08/21/preflightingapplication-errors-0xe8000001-and-others.aspx">24100.net</a> (very detailed and helpful)</li>
	<li><a href="http://discussions.apple.com/thread.jspa?threadID=1721273&amp;tstart=0">Apple</a> (a developer discussion thread)</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fire season again]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2008/10/fire-season-again/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2008/10/fire-season-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[This year the fires are hitting a little closer to home. (Fortunately, everything seems to be OK so far.) A couple weeks ago there was a <a href="http://www.venturacountystar.com/news/2008/oct/12/fire-burns-7-acres-in-ventura-river-bed/">fire in the Ventura River bottom</a>. Today, a <a href="http://www.venturacountystar.com/news/2008/oct/22/small-fire-ventura/">more serious fire</a> started on the edge of town and moved up into the hills. The entire hillside burned, but by the time I saw it, it was just a black hill with a bit of smoke coming off. It must have gone over the ridge, since helicopters were dropping water there. (I can still hear them as I write this.) But there wasn&#8217;t much smoke coming from the area. It looks like the wind has died for the evening, so I would be surprised if it flares up again.

But, it looks like a bigger fire must have started up the coast towards Santa Barbra, because there is a lot of smoke blowing out to sea from much farther west.

I took a picture of the sunset and smoke with my iPhone, but can&#8217;t seem to get it off the phone without a lot of extra hassle. (Apple has been a big disappointment lately, but that&#8217;s another story.)

<a href="http://delicious.com/tomwhipple/REDFLAG">Other relevant links. </a>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Configuring CVS for Apple's XCode projects]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2008/10/configuring-cvs-for-apples-xcode-projects/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2008/10/configuring-cvs-for-apples-xcode-projects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<em>UPDATE: It seems that most of the nonsense described below is fixed in XCode 3.1.2. However it is still necessary to import the project and then check it out again.</em>

Apple ostensibly has integrated CVS &amp; SVN as version control into XCode. But in XCode 3.1.1 the CVS integration is very poor. The problem seems to be the project/build directory where XCode keeps binaries. This directory appears to be generated from all the other files, so the solution seems to be to leave it out of CVS.

These steps seem to work:
<ol>
	<li>Make sure the repository is set up. (See <a href="http://developer.apple.com/internet/opensource/cvsoverview.html">Apple&#8217;s instructions</a> or better yet, the <a href="http://ximbiot.com/cvs/manual/">CVS manual</a>) This includes defining the repository under SCM in XCode.</li>
	<li>Create the project in a temporary directory as normal in XCode.</li>
	<li>Go to <strong>SCM&gt;Configure SCM for this project</strong>. Choose your repository and click OK.</li>
	<li>Go to <strong>Build&gt;Clean All Targets</strong>.</li>
	<li>Close the project window.</li>
	<li>Go to the project directory in the Finder and delete the contents of the &#8220;build&#8221; directory.</li>
	<li>In XCode, go to <strong>SCM&gt;Repositories</strong> tool.</li>
	<li>Click &#8220;Import&#8221; and import the temporary project directory into CVS.</li>
	<li>Click &#8220;Checkout&#8221; and choose the directory where you will do your work. (This is NOT the temporary project directory you created in step 2.)</li>
	<li>XCode will ask you if you want to open the project when it is done with the checkout. If the checkout directory structure looks good, you should delete the temporary directory.</li>
</ol>
NOTE: If some subset of the builds directory shows up under the SCM tool on the left of the project tab, go to <strong>SCM&gt;Refresh Entire Project </strong>BEFORE the build directory gets committed.
NOTE 2: If the build directory gets committed by mistake, delete it from the repository, the local directory structure, and the corresponding entry in the projectdir/CVS/Entries file.
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our Congress has failed us]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2008/09/our-congress-has-failed-us/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2008/09/our-congress-has-failed-us</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[The stock market has lost something like 10% in a SINGLE DAY. All because the congress couldn&#8217;t figure out what the hell they are doing. Rather than waiting and forming a stable consensus, they brought the bill to a vote and <em>let it fail</em>. In doing so they have failed the country. All 435 members of the house share in this responsibility equally. If they voted for it, they failed to do enough to build consensus with their colleagues. If they voted against it, they need to explain to the country why they didn&#8217;t raise the objection before.

I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve ever done it before, but I wrote my congressman (R-CA) about it:
<blockquote>I see from your website that you voted against today&#8217;s financial bailout bill. As a result of your action, the stock market has declined dramatically. We have been hearing from various experts for the past several days that the situation is very bad, yet you have ignored this advice and contributed to an escalation of the problem.

You are therefore personally responsible for the decline in the market. Allowing such an important bill to fail is irresponsible. As a member of congress, you are part of a very small group of national leaders. Safeguarding the health of our economy is just as important as protecting our physical security. It is part of your responsibility as a leader and duty as an American to put politics and ideology aside in this time of crisis and figure out a way out of this situation.

If you and your colleagues cannot support the bill as proposed, you must work together to come up with a reasonable solution, before it is put to a vote. We saw the result of this failure in the market today. You are all, Democrat and Republican, equally responsible for this result. Each one of you owes the country and your constituents a detailed explanation of your position and reasoning.</blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone 2.1 software: FAIL]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2008/09/iphone-21-software-fail/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2008/09/iphone-21-software-fail</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[So far, the new iPhone software released on Friday doesn&#8217;t look good. I&#8217;ve had two problems in as many days.

Yesterday, the bluetooth headset did not deactivate after a call ended until after I unlocked the phone with the slider dodad.

But the worst happened today. I was driving down the PCH enjoying the day and a listening to a podcast when my phone decided to stop playing the podcast and dial a friend. At first I thought he was calling me, but after an awkward confused silence I realized what had happened. Needless to say, this is very bizarre and totally unacceptable. Imagine being in the middle of a personal conversation when your phone decides to call a random contact!!

So, 2.0.1 is still looking pretty good.
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Huh??]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2008/09/huh/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2008/09/huh</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Speaking of the PCH:
<p style="text-align: center"><img src="http://tomwhipple.com/img/badsign.JPG" title="WARNING: persons present in the Santa Monica Palisades Bluff are prohibited by SMMC" alt="WARNING: persons present in the Santa Monica Palisades Bluff are prohibited by SMMC" height="356" width="393" /></p>
What??

Isn&#8217;t it just easier to say &#8220;KEEP OUT&#8221; or &#8220;NO TRESPASSING&#8221;?
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
