<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: misc | Tom Whipple]]></title>
  <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/category/misc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-29T21:18:05-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tomwhipple.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tom Whipple]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What does an IT department say about a company?]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2015/03/what-does-your-it-department-say-about-your-company/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-29T20:52:43-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2015/03/what-does-your-it-department-say-about-your-company</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been thinking about the proper role of an IT department in a tech company lately&hellip; Is it a trusted partner, helping unlock productivity of highly talented people? Or is it to keep mischevious employees on a short leash.</p>

<p>The answer says a lot about the whole company.</p>

<p>It comes down to this question: Do you trust your team? If you assume that everyone is genuinely striving to use their best judgment to advance your company&rsquo;s business, then the IT team is a key contributor to the shared outcome. They are the subject matter experts who&rsquo;s advice is valued and sought out by all employees. They keep up to date with the best tools &amp; practices, and are eager to adopt new technologies when they become available. Obviously, real threats, internal and external, do exist. So, IT must also have the capability to ensure that people can be held accountable for the judgments they make. In short, the working model is &ldquo;trust but verify&rdquo;.</p>

<p>This is the kind of environment I want to work in.</p>

<p>However, if you view your employees as soulless minions who can&rsquo;t be trusted to flip a light switch correctly, then the IT must adopt the centralized controlling role of an ever-present big brother. Every user&rsquo;s action must be scrutinized. No new application can be permitted without multiple levels of approval. If a new tool becomes available, agreements must be signed, audits must be completed, and at all costs PROCESS MUST BE FOLLOWED.</p>

<p>Of course audits &amp; process have direct and indirect costs. Why is Enterprise software obscenely expensive? Here&rsquo;s a hint: enterprise software companies are good at two things: Process and sales. Absent: Actually producing well designed software.</p>

<p>But, the indirect costs of the centralized approach can be even more severe. Technology companies rely on smart, creative people applying their creativity to the main challenges the business faces. High performing teams use the best available tools, changing rapidly as better tools become available.  But, if the menu of choices is limited to those selected by an overworked IT team with limited motivation to stay on top of the best available tools, otherwise productive teams are crippled before they even begin work.</p>

<p>The working model here is &ldquo;trust no one.&rdquo; But, the logic here is circular. Otherwise productive energy is spent figuring out how to get normal work done. Sometimes that effort goes in to understanding &amp; compiling with over-burdensome process. But sometimes the process is so burdensome that it must be worked around. Of course that&rsquo;s &ldquo;outside of policy&rdquo; and further justification that users can&rsquo;t be trusted!</p>

<p>This environment is toxic, and not somewhere I would want to work.</p>

<p>So, think carefully: Which kind of IT department should your company have?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Etiquette for Recruiters]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2011/05/etiquette-for-recruiters/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2011/05/etiquette-for-recruiters</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ok, here are some dos &amp; don'ts for all you recruiters out there:</p>

<ul>
    <li><strong>DON'T cold call me just because I've just connected with someone you know on LinkedIn.</strong></li>
    <li>DON'T pretend that I should know who you are. - If you've never spoken to me before, an introduction is appropriate.</li>
    <li>DON'T just use random keywords from my blog and profile and assume they define me. Just because I've written about an SEO talk I went to two years ago doesn't mean that I do SEO a living. (Hint: My resume &amp; profile talk about software development. SEO is <em>not</em> software development).</li>
    <li>DON'T just pass on my name and number to a co-worker without any context.</li>
    <li>DO <em>email</em> me with an introduction and specific details and, if you must call, ask for a good  time to do so.</li>
    <li>DO know who I am and what I do <em>before</em> you call.</li>
    <li>DO understand that my time is valuable and that, as a contractor,  I'm losing money if I'm talking to you.</li>
</ul>


<p>(And in case you are thinking about contacting me, I&rsquo;m not looking for new opportunities at the moment.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing Smartovation Technologies!]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2009/08/announcing-smartovation-technologies/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2009/08/announcing-smartovation-technologies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am very pleased to announce the launch of <a title="Smartovation Technologies" href="http://www.smartovation.com">Smartovation Technologies</a>, a new venture devoted to iPhone and web applications. We expect to be able to submit at least one new App this month. Stay tuned for updates!</p>




<p>And, work continues on the <a href="http://www.walki-talki.com">walki-talk.com</a> audio tour guides.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fire season again]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2008/10/fire-season-again/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2008/10/fire-season-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This year the fires are hitting a little closer to home. (Fortunately, everything seems to be OK so far.) A couple weeks ago there was a <a href="http://www.venturacountystar.com/news/2008/oct/12/fire-burns-7-acres-in-ventura-river-bed/">fire in the Ventura River bottom</a>. Today, a <a href="http://www.venturacountystar.com/news/2008/oct/22/small-fire-ventura/">more serious fire</a> started on the edge of town and moved up into the hills. The entire hillside burned, but by the time I saw it, it was just a black hill with a bit of smoke coming off. It must have gone over the ridge, since helicopters were dropping water there. (I can still hear them as I write this.) But there wasn&rsquo;t much smoke coming from the area. It looks like the wind has died for the evening, so I would be surprised if it flares up again.</p>

<p>But, it looks like a bigger fire must have started up the coast towards Santa Barbra, because there is a lot of smoke blowing out to sea from much farther west.</p>

<p>I took a picture of the sunset and smoke with my iPhone, but can&rsquo;t seem to get it off the phone without a lot of extra hassle. (Apple has been a big disappointment lately, but that&rsquo;s another story.)</p>

<p><a href="http://delicious.com/tomwhipple/REDFLAG">Other relevant links. </a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Huh??]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2008/09/huh/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2008/09/huh</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Speaking of the PCH:</p>

<p style="text-align: center"><img src="http://tomwhipple.com/img/badsign.JPG" title="WARNING: persons present in the Santa Monica Palisades Bluff are prohibited by SMMC" alt="WARNING: persons present in the Santa Monica Palisades Bluff are prohibited by SMMC" height="356" width="393" /></p>


<p>What??</p>

<p>Isn&rsquo;t it just easier to say &ldquo;KEEP OUT&rdquo; or &ldquo;NO TRESPASSING&rdquo;?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
