<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Misc | Tom Whipple]]></title>
  <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/category/misc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-13T15:37:54-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tomwhipple.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tom Whipple]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Etiquette for Recruiters]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2011/05/etiquette-for-recruiters/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2011/05/etiquette-for-recruiters</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ok, here are some dos &amp; don'ts for all you recruiters out there:</p>

<ul>
    <li><strong>DON'T cold call me just because I've just connected with someone you know on LinkedIn.</strong></li>
    <li>DON'T pretend that I should know who you are. - If you've never spoken to me before, an introduction is appropriate.</li>
    <li>DON'T just use random keywords from my blog and profile and assume they define me. Just because I've written about an SEO talk I went to two years ago doesn't mean that I do SEO a living. (Hint: My resume &amp; profile talk about software development. SEO is <em>not</em> software development).</li>
    <li>DON'T just pass on my name and number to a co-worker without any context.</li>
    <li>DO <em>email</em> me with an introduction and specific details and, if you must call, ask for a good  time to do so.</li>
    <li>DO know who I am and what I do <em>before</em> you call.</li>
    <li>DO understand that my time is valuable and that, as a contractor,  I'm losing money if I'm talking to you.</li>
</ul>


<p>(And in case you are thinking about contacting me, I'm not looking for new opportunities at the moment.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing Smartovation Technologies!]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2009/08/announcing-smartovation-technologies/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2009/08/announcing-smartovation-technologies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am very pleased to announce the launch of <a title="Smartovation Technologies" href="http://www.smartovation.com">Smartovation Technologies</a>, a new venture devoted to iPhone and web applications. We expect to be able to submit at least one new App this month. Stay tuned for updates!</p>




<p>And, work continues on the <a href="http://www.walki-talki.com">walki-talk.com</a> audio tour guides.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fire season again]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2008/10/fire-season-again/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2008/10/fire-season-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This year the fires are hitting a little closer to home. (Fortunately, everything seems to be OK so far.) A couple weeks ago there was a <a href="http://www.venturacountystar.com/news/2008/oct/12/fire-burns-7-acres-in-ventura-river-bed/">fire in the Ventura River bottom</a>. Today, a <a href="http://www.venturacountystar.com/news/2008/oct/22/small-fire-ventura/">more serious fire</a> started on the edge of town and moved up into the hills. The entire hillside burned, but by the time I saw it, it was just a black hill with a bit of smoke coming off. It must have gone over the ridge, since helicopters were dropping water there. (I can still hear them as I write this.) But there wasn't much smoke coming from the area. It looks like the wind has died for the evening, so I would be surprised if it flares up again.</p>

<p>But, it looks like a bigger fire must have started up the coast towards Santa Barbra, because there is a lot of smoke blowing out to sea from much farther west.</p>

<p>I took a picture of the sunset and smoke with my iPhone, but can't seem to get it off the phone without a lot of extra hassle. (Apple has been a big disappointment lately, but that's another story.)</p>

<p><a href="http://delicious.com/tomwhipple/REDFLAG">Other relevant links. </a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Huh??]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2008/09/huh/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2008/09/huh</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Speaking of the PCH:</p>

<p style="text-align: center"><img src="http://tomwhipple.com/img/badsign.JPG" title="WARNING: persons present in the Santa Monica Palisades Bluff are prohibited by SMMC" alt="WARNING: persons present in the Santa Monica Palisades Bluff are prohibited by SMMC" height="356" width="393" /></p>


<p>What??</p>

<p>Isn't it just easier to say "KEEP OUT" or "NO TRESPASSING"?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wow ... It's been a while]]></title>
    <link href="http://tomwhipple.com/2008/06/wow-its-been-a-while/"/>
    <updated>2008-06-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tomwhipple.com/2008/06/wow-its-been-a-while</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>But, I'm still alive.</p>

<p>After my own server died a few months ago, I finally have my website moved over to laughingsquid.net. As far as I can tell everything is now back up and running.</p>

<p align="center"> <a href="http://www.laughingsquid.com"><img src="http://www.laughingsquid.net/images/powered_white.gif" alt="Powered by Laughing Squid" width="150" height="50" border="0" /></a></p>


<p>Most of the outage has been due to my own laziness. I haven't been motivated to keep the site up lately. But, Laughing Squid seems to have very responsive servers, which is far more than I can say about godaddy.com.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
